[
    {
        "question": "To kickstart your journey in the field of Full Stack Development. Watch Our Video on Full Stack Developer Interview Questions",
        "answer": "Basic Full Stack Developer Interview Questions for Freshers\nFirstly let’s discuss some entry-level questions that you can expect during an interview, these questions are pretty easy and can be answered if you have even basic knowledge of the topics.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "1. Mention all the ways by which we can include the CSS code in an HTML code.",
        "answer": "Cascading Style Sheets – CSS, or Cascading Style Sheets, is a language used to style an HTML document. It specifies how an HTML element will appear on a web page.\nHyper Text Markup Language – HTML refers to a markup language which is used to construct the basic structure of a web page.\nWays to include CSS code in an HTML document –\nInline Method – In this method, the CSS code is included using the style keyword as an attribute in HTML tags.\nExample <p style = “font-size: 10;”> Intellipaat </p> -Intellipaat\nInternal Method – We have to use tag intag that is the head section of the HTML document.\n\nExternal Method – We use tag to include a CSS file in the HTML document.\n\nReady to test your Full Stack skills?\nTake our quiz now and ace those interview questions!\nTake a Quiz",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. Explain in brief, what is meant by the term Semantic Elements in HTML.",
        "answer": "Semantics Elements – Semantic Elements in an HTML document are the elements which clearly describe themselves to both the browser and the developer. Semantic elements make HTML more understandable by defining different sections and layouts of the web page in a more readable manner.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. Describe tags, attributes, and elements in HTML.",
        "answer": "Tags in HTML – In HTML, tags refer to keywords that are enclosed inside angular brackets and are used to display the HTML elements.\nAttributes in HTML – Attributes are the entities which are used to show the features and additional properties of an HTML element.\nHTML Elements – HTML elements are a collection of HTML attributes and HTML tags that are used to display the content of an HTML page on the user’s screen.\nCheck out the Top Web Developer Interview Questions.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. What is JavaScript? Explain any four libraries used in JavaScript.",
        "answer": "JavaScript –\nJavaScript is a typescript-based, general-purpose programming language that works on the principles of object-oriented programming.\nJavaScript happens to be a very popular programming language which is used for both server-side and client-side scripting.\nThere are three ways by which we can include JavaScript in our HTML document-\nEmbedded Coding- In this method we use the <script> tag in the HTML document to include JavaScript code.\nInternal Linking – In this we use HTML event attributes.\nExample - <a href=\"#\" onClick=\"alert('Intellipaat's Website is Ready !');\">Okay!</a>\nExternal Linking – Here we use <script> tag with an attribute src.\nSyntax - <script src=\"intellipaat.js\">\nFour Libraries used in JavaScript –\nJavaScript is a revolutionary programming language which has transformed the way how world wide web used to work. Libraries in JS cover all the domains of development.\nFor example, Vue.Js, React Js, Angular.Js, Next.Js, Node.Js, Express.Js, and many more.\nReact Js – React Js is a type of JavaScript-based open-source framework developed by Meta. The main purpose for the introduction of this premium framework was to build an intuitive UI for web applications.\nExpress.js – Express.js, or just Express, is a Node. js-based back-end web application framework for building RESTful APIs that are free and open-source under the MIT License. It is designed for the creation of web applications and APIs.\nNext.Js – Next.Js is an open-source React framework based on JavaScript. The framework extends the functionality of React-based web applications including server-side rendering and the generation of static websites. The framework is developed by Vercel.\nVue.js – Vue.js is a free and open-source JavaScript model-view-ViewModel front-end framework for creating user interfaces and single-page applications.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. State the definition of the Callback function in JavaScript, and also give the code snippet as an example.",
        "answer": "The callback function in JavaScript is a type of function which passed as arguments to another function. Irrespective of the sequence by which the functions have been defined it is executed based on the function calls. The execution takes place after the execution of the previous function has been completed.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. Expand the term MEAN stack and MERN stack, and mention their alternatives.",
        "answer": "MEAN stack – MongoDB, Express.Js, Angular.Js, Node.Js\nMERN stack – MongoDB, Express.Js, React.Js, Node.Js\nStacks are prepared based on compatibility between different technologies. A few of the efficient stacks are –\nMEVN – MongoDB, Express.Js, Vue.Js, Node.Js. MEVN is used to develop full-stack applications efficiently and effectively. It is a to-go alternative for MERN and MEAN.\nLAMP – Linux, Apache, MySQL, PHP. It is one of the most popular cloud-based application development stacks.\nPERN – PostgreSQL, Express.Js, React.Js, Node.Js. PERN is used to develop applications based on CRUD operations.\nGet 100% Hike!\nMaster Most in Demand Skills Now !\nBy providing your contact details, you agree to our Terms of Use & Privacy Policy",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. What is meant by scope in Angular Js? Also, define the different types.",
        "answer": "In Angular.Js the term “Scope” refers to a binding part between HTML’s view and JavaScript’s controller. Also, it contains the application’s data and objects. There are two types of scope in Angular.Js –\n$scope – A $scope is a JavaScript object used to communicate between the controller and the view. $scope essentially connects a view (DOM element) to the ViewModel and functions provided in a controller.\n$rootScope – The top-most scope in Angular.Js is $rootScope. There can only be one $rootScope in an app, which is shared by all components. As a result, it acts in the same way as a global variable. All other $scopes are children of the $rootScope.\nPrepare yourself for next interview with .NET Developer Interview Questions.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. Briefly explain Directives in Angular Js.",
        "answer": "Directives in Angular are described as classes that can add new functionality to template components or alter current behaviour. Directives in Angular are used to manipulate the DOM, whether by adding new elements to the DOM, deleting ones, or modifying the look of the DOM elements.\nThere are three types of directives present in Angular.Js –\nComponent Directive\nAttribute Directive\nStructural Directive\nTake a look at the most asked WordPress Developer Interview Questions! Prepared by our experts and crack the interview.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. What are the features of Node Js? Also, mention why it’s a single-threaded framework.",
        "answer": "Node.Js is a very popular framework, that is used for back-end development. It uses a powerful V8 JavaScript engine which is used to execute JavaScript code outside of the browser. Node.Js facilitates developers a lot in back-end development, various pointers due to which Node.Js is preferred by the developers are –\nOpen-Source Framework\nAsynchronous Programming\nUtility of NPM\nHigh Performance\nHigh Uptime\nHigh Scalability\nSingle-Threaded Framework\nNode.Js is a type of single-threaded framework. The working principle of Node.Js is based upon single-threaded event loop model architecture similar to that of JavaScript which is used to handle multiple client requests.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. Define and expand the term NPM. Why do we use NPM with Node.Js?",
        "answer": "NPM (Node Package Manager) is a type of JavaScript software registry over the web that is used by developers to share, download, and borrow various types of packages that are used for installation and dependencies resolving purposes.\nNode Package Manager has three different types of components –\nWebsite – The website is used for package discovery and profile management.\nCommand Line Interface – CLI is a type of terminal used to run NPM in the developer’s system.\nRegistry – A registry is a type of database which have JavaScript files and associated metadata.\nIn Node.Js Node Package Manager is used to set up the Node.Js development environment in the user’s system, download the needed packages, and resolve dependencies issues.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. What is CORS? How to include CORS in Express.Js?",
        "answer": "CORS  (Cross-Origin Resource Sharing) – CORS is a browser mechanism that allows web pages in one domain to have limited access to resources in other domains (cross-domain requests). This enables browser client scripts to interact with and access resources from different origins.\nAs a result, the SOP is extended and made more flexible (Same-Origin Policy). Same-origin restrictions limit a website’s access to resources outside its source domain. CORS allows access to diverse online resources across several domains. CORS can be used to integrate web scripts when they request a resource with an external origin (protocol, domain, or port) from their own.\nTo enable cross-origin resource sharing In Express.Js we use CORS NPM modules. First, we have to install CORS in the system, and then we have to enable CORS for Express.Js. If CORS is not configured correctly then the website is vulnerable to CSRF (Cross-Site Request Forgery) attacks.\nCheck out our PHP Interview Questions to ace your next interview!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "12. What is meant by the term “Replication” in MongoDB?",
        "answer": "Replication in MongoDB happens to be a practice of syncing data across several servers. With numerous copies of data on separate database servers, replication offers redundancy and boosts data availability. Replication safeguards a database against the loss of a single server. Users may also recover from hardware failures and service interruptions through replication. Users can assign one copy of the data to disaster recovery, reporting, or backup.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "13. Mention the ways by which we can create a new database in PostgreSQL.",
        "answer": "There are two ways by which we can create a new database in PostgreSQL–\nUsing pgAdmin – In this method, we use the GUI provided by pgAdmin to create the PostgreSQL database.\nUsing SQL Shell – Here, in this method, we use the CLI provided by the SQL. Users have to write commands in the SQL shell for the creation of a new database.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "14. What is the difference between the WHERE clause and the HAVING clause?",
        "answer": "Difference between WHERE clause and HAVING clause-\nWHERE Clause HAVING Clause\nIt is used to filter out the records from a table on the basis of a specified condition. It is used to filter out the records from a group on the basis of a specified condition.\nWe can use the WHERE clause without using the GROUP BY clause. Also, the WHERE clause is row-major. We cannot use the HAVING clause without using the GROUP BY clause. Also, the HAVING clause is column-major.\nThe WHERE clause cannot accommodate aggregate function and can implement statements like SELECT, UPDATE, and DELETE. The HAVING clause can accommodate aggregate function and can only implement a SELECT statement.\nThe WHERE clause is used before the GROUP BY clause. The HAVING clause is used after the GROUP BY clause.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "15. Define RDBMS. How do RDBMS and DBMS differ from each other?",
        "answer": "The acronym RDBMS refers to Relational Database Management System. An RDBMS is a type of DBMS which is used to store data in a tabular form based on rows, it connects similar data components. An RDBMS provides features that ensure data security, correctness, integrity, and consistency. It’s essentially a tool that lets users build, remove, and update relational databases. A relational database is a database system that stores and retrieves data in the form of rows and columns in a tabular format.\nDifference between RDBMS and DBMS-\nRDBMS DBMS\nRDBMS is used to store data in tabular form. The data stored is indexed and stored in rows. It is used to store data in the form of a file.\nMultiple data elements can be accessed at the same time in RDBMS. In DBMS, only individual data elements can be accessed.\nThe concept of normalization is followed in RDBMS, with a sort of relation between the data. The concept of normalization is not present in DBMS, also the relationship between the data elements is absent.\nRDBMS support distributed database which is capable of dealing with a larger amount of data. DBMS is used for smaller amounts of data, it is incapable of handling distributed system.\nMySQL, PostgreSQL, SQL Server, and Oracle are a few examples. Examples include XML and the Windows Registry.\nHere we conclude our basics. Expect these questions in your interviews. In the coming up section, we will enlighten you with a bit tougher questions, sit tight as a big knowledge pit is waiting for you.\nIf the field of Full Stack Development thrills you, enroll in our Full Stack Web Developer Course using MEAN stack.\n\nIntermediate Full Stack Developer Interview Questions\nWelcome to yet another section of the blog. In the previous section we covered the basics, and I hope it gave you an idea of what the recruiters seek in the basics. In this section of the blog, we will talk about the intermediary level of questions with their answers. These questions seek an in-depth understanding of the concepts present in the technology.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "16. In what real-life scenarios should we consider MongoDB for our database?",
        "answer": "When your data is document-centric and does not integrate well within the schema of a relational database, when you want to support vast size, when you are rapidly prototyping, and in a few other circumstances, NoSQL databases like MongoDB are an excellent solution.\nPossible use cases for MongoDB are as follows –\nProduct Data Management System\nOperational Intelligence\nProduct Catalogue\nMainframe Offloading\nReal-Time Data Integration",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "17. In PostgreSQL, what is meant by Cluster and Non-Cluster Indexes?",
        "answer": "Cluster Indexes – It is a type of index used in PostgreSQL that is used to arrange rows of data in a database based on their key values. There can only be one index based on clustering in a table in a PostgreSQL database. These clustered indexes may also be used to decide the order of the data, which is how data is stored in the database. Typically, the primary key in an RDBMS allows you to construct a clustered index based on that single column.\nNon-Cluster Indexes – In non-clustered indexing, the data and its associated index is kept separately the concept of pointer works here, there exists a pointer pointing towards the location of data. This type of indexing is also known as secondary indexing. There can exist multiple non-clustered indexes based on the specified table in a PostgreSQL database. Based on the comparison between cluster index and non-cluster indexing, cluster indexing is of a larger size.\nAlso, check out the blog on difference between PostgreSQL and MySQL.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "18. State the difference between the DROP command and the TRUNCATE command in SQL.",
        "answer": "The difference between the DROP command and the TRUNCATE command in SQL are as follows-\nDROP Command TRUNCATE Command\nDrop is used to remove the whole table from the database. In a database we use the Truncate command is used to delete all the rows present in the table.\nThe Drop command deletes the whole structure of the table present in the database also it frees the memory allocated. The Truncate command does not delete the whole structure of the table from the database also does not free the allocated memory.\nOnce the DROP command is applied the action cannot be undone. The TRUNCATE command can be undone.\nThe execution speed of the DROP command is slower as compared to the TRUNCATE command. The execution speed of the TRUNCATE command is faster compared to the DROP command.\nThe view table does not exist in the DROP command. The view table is present in the TRUNCATE command.\nSyntax –\nDROP TABLE Intellipaat; Syntax  –\nTRUNCATE TABLE Intellipaat;",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "19. Explain the concepts of Buffers and Streams in Node.Js.",
        "answer": "Buffers – Buffers in Node.Js refers to the pieces of memory allocated on the user’s system used to store raw binary data. Users can only once set the size of the buffer cannot be changed. Buffers can only handle binary data and cannot be resized, and buffer possesses similarities to an array but, arrays are resizable. A byte is represented by each integer in a buffer. To print the Buffer instance, use the console.log() method.\nStreams – In Node.Js, the term “Stream” refers to an abstract interface that is used with the working of streaming data during a process. To implement the stream interface, we use an API provided by node:stream. There can exist various stream objects in Node.Js.\nTypes of stream in Node.Js –\nReadable Stream – It is a type of stream in Node.Js that is used to create a stream of data for reading purposes.\nWritable Stream – Writable stream is used to create a stream of data for writing purposes.\nDuplex Stream – In Node.Js, duplex stream refers to a type of stream that is created to make a stream of data which is capable of reading and writing.\nTransform Stream – It is a type of stream that is used to create a stream of data for both reading and writing purposes but we can change the data during the process of reading and writing.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "20. What do you understand by the term Scaffolding in Express.Js? Does MVC support Scaffolding?",
        "answer": "The term “Scaffolding” in Express.Js refers to the creation of a  basic skeleton structure for the to-be-developed web application. Scaffolding helps users to create their profiles in the public domain. Also, scaffolding helps in the addition of middleware in the application, the creation of separate route files, and many more. It starts the basic building of the application for us.\nExplore these top JavaScript Interview Questions and ace your next interview to get your dream job!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "21. Differentiate between these technologies; Node.Js and Django.",
        "answer": "Below-mentioned is the differentiating pointers based on which Node Js and Django differ from each other-\nNode.Js Django\nNode.Js is a type of open-source framework based on JavaScript which is used to develop web applications. Django is a type of open-source framework based on Python which is used to develop web applications.\nThe framework Node.Js is developed using three programming languages namely C, CPP, and JavaScript. The framework Django is developed using Python programming language.\nApplications developed using Node.Js are more scalable as compared to applications developed in Django. Applications developed using Django are less scalable as compared to the applications developed using Node.Js.\nNode.Js follows the concept of event-driven programming. Django follows the concept of Model View Template architecture at the time of development.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "22. Why do we do interpolation in Angular.Js? Briefly explain the ways by which Angular Js extends HTML.",
        "answer": "Interpolation in Angular.Js refers to the way by which we transfer data from any TypeScript code to an HTML view. By using this method we can encapsulate expressions between texts to evaluate the value of the expression. Interpolation in Angular.Js works on one-way data binding. By using this we can bind data to our logic whereas,, we can only use string parameters.\nSyntax of Interpolation – {{expression}}\nAngular.Js uses directives to bind the HTML data with the Angular.Js application, it extends HTML in three ways –\nng-app – This directive in Angular.Js is used to define the Angular.Js application that we want to develop.\nnp-model – We use this directive to bind the value of HTML controls.\nng-bind – In Angular.Js, this directive is used to bind the HTML view and the application data.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "23. What are State and Prop in React Js? Explain briefly the concept by giving examples.",
        "answer": "State in React Js – The term “State” in React Js refers to a type of variable that exists inside a component and is used to store data or information about the component. The state has a similar working principle as that of a local variable it cannot be accessed or modified outside its component. To modify the state we have to use this.setState, when this is applied the state class re-renders itself.\nExample of State –\n\nProp in React Js – In React Js, the term “Prop” is an alias name given to properties where it acts like an object which is used to store attribute values associated with various types of tags. The working principle of props is similar to HTML attributes. Props behave as a read-only component in React Js. Props are immutable.\nExample of Prop –",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "24. What is the difference between var, const and let keywords in JavaScript?",
        "answer": "Below-mentioned are the differentiating pointers between var, const, and let variables-\nvar Variable const Variable let Variable\nVar variables can change their values and can be re-declared again inside its scope. Const variables cannot be re-declared and it cannot change their values within its scope. Let variables can change their values but they cannot be re-declared inside its scope.\nInitialization is needed for var variables. Initialization is needed for const variables. Initialization is not needed for const variables.\nIt has a functional scope. It has a block scope. It has a block scope.\nAccessing var variables without initialization is possible. Const variables cannot be accessed without initialization. Without initialization let variables cannot be accessed.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "25. What is DOM manipulation? How it is different from BOM? Explain the related information in detail.",
        "answer": "DOM Manipulation – DOM (Document Object Model) in JavaScript refers to a hierarchical tree-like structure which is used to show the relationship between various types of HTML elements. The working principle of DOM is very simple; it is a tree of nodes created by the browser. Each node contains distinct attributes and methods that may be modified with JavaScript.\nDifference between DOM and BOM –\nDOM BOM\nThe full form of DOM is the Document Object Model. The full form of BOM is the Browser Object Model.\nThe DOM is used for HTML document manipulation. The BOM is used for manipulation and accessing the browser window.\nIt has a standard set of rules on which DOM works. It does not have a standard set of rules, each browser has its unique standard rules.\nDOM is the subset of BOM. BOM is the superset of DOM.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "26. State the different ways by which we can create objects in JavaScript.",
        "answer": "There are three different ways by which we can create objects in JavaScript and they are as follows-\nUsing object literal.\n\nBy creating an instance of an Object directly.\n\nBy using the constructor function.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "27. Comment on Box Model in Cascading Style Sheets.",
        "answer": "One of the most basic ideas in Cascading Style Sheets is the CSS Box Model. The Box Model in CSS refers to a type of container which is used to design the layout of a web page from scratch, it consists of various properties like margin, padding, border, and content area. The web browser renders each element as a rectangular box in accordance with the CSS box model.\nIn CSS, Box-Model has several properties which are stated below-\nContent: This property is used to show text, images, and other elements that can have their sizes adjusted using the width and height properties.\nPadding: This attribute is used to add space inside any defined borders around the element.\nBorder: This property is used to define the style, colour, and width of the border as well as to cover the content and any padding.\nMargin: The border region of an element is surrounded by space created by this attribute.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "28. What are the various kinds of CSS selectors? Explain.",
        "answer": "Selectors in CSS refer to ways which are used to locate a particular HTML element in the CSS file to style. In CSS, there are five types of selectors, they are –\nSimple Selectors – In simple selectors, we select elements based on their id, class, and name.\nCombinator Selectors – In this, elements are selected based on the relationship between them.\nPseudo-Class Selectors – This selects elements based on their state.\nPseudo-Elements Selectors – This type of selector selects a part of the HTML elements and styles it.\nAttribute Selectors – Attribute Selectors are used to styling an HTML element based on its attribute or its attribute value.\n\nAlso, check out the blog on CSS selector in Selenium.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "29. What is a table in an HTML document? Mention all the associated tags to it.",
        "answer": "A table in HTML is a collection of rows and columns which is defined using <table> tag. An HTML document consists of various types of tags associated with table tags.\nTags Description\n<table> This tag is used to define a table.\n<th> <th> is used to define a header cell in an HTML table.\n<tr> We use <tr> tag to define a row in an HTML table.\n<td> It is used to define a cell in an HTML table.\n<caption> In HTML, <caption> tag is used to caption a table.\n<colgroup> It is used in HTML and documents to group multiple columns in tables.\n<col> <col> tag is used to specify properties for columns inside a <colgroup> tag.\n<thead> Grouping of the header content.\n<tbody> Grouping of the body content.\n<tfoot> Grouping of the footer content.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "30. Explain different types of media tags in HTML. Also, give their syntax as well.",
        "answer": "Various types of media tags in HTML are as follows –\n<audio>: To incorporate sound files into a web page we use <audio> tag, which is a type of inline element.\n<audio>\n            <source src=”sample.mp3″ type=”audio/mpeg”>\n</audio>\n<video>: We use <video> tag to embed videos in our HTML document.\n<video src=” ” controls>   </video>\n<source>: In HTML, <source> tag is used to attach multimedia files like audio, video, and pictures to an HTML document.\n<source src=” ” type=” “>\n   …\n</source>\n<embed>: In an HTML document, <embed> tag is used to embed external apps, most of which provide multimedia information like audio or video.\n<embed attributes>\n<track>: It is used to provide text files that should be viewable while the video is playing, such as subtitles, caption files, or other text-containing files. As a result, the sectors for the audio and video elements are straightforward.\n<track Attribute>\nAlright, it was a bit much but guess what, you have gained a lot of knowledge which will help you to crack your dream job. Coming up is an advanced level of knowledge is waiting for you, the amount of knowledge you will gain will leave you in awe!\nHave any experience with Python? Check out our Python Web Development tutorial and be an ace.\n\nAdvanced Full Stack Developer Interview Questions for Experienced\nFirst of all, I congratulate you on making it to the end, I hope you have cleared all the concepts previously mentioned before. Now welcome to the final section of the blog, so far we have covered thirty questions ranging from easy to medium difficulty. Now, it the time to exceed our limits and go for the real thing.\nIn this section of the blog, we are going to offer you a huge knowledge dump which will cover the rest of the leftover topics in the field of full-stack web development.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "31. What is the concept of routing in Angular.Js? Explain its significance as well.",
        "answer": "Routing in Angular.Js refers to the way by which users can switch between various web pages while using a single-page web application. This technique allows the users to develop different types of URLs that can be used to navigate through different components of the web application.\nTo do this ngRoute module is used by the developers to access various components of the web page without reloading the whole application, this must be done after adding the ngRoute module to the dependencies.\nBecause of the concept of routing in Angular.Js, the developers can prepare a single-page web application that can redirect to different web pages.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "32. What is the difference between ng-show and ng-if directives in Angular.Js?",
        "answer": "It has been seen that both terminologies show similar behaviour. These terms usually govern the performance of the web application developed using Angular.Js Check out the difference between them to have a better understanding of them-\nng-show Directive ng-if Directive\nThis directive is used to hide or show the HTML elements depending on the expression provided by the attribute. This directive is used to recreate or remove a part of the DOM tree depending upon the expression provided.\nIt can be used to hide and show the rendered data in the application. It only processes the data if the given condition is true.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "33. What does the term React Hooks refer?",
        "answer": "The concept was first introduced in React version 16.8. After the introduction, the developers were able to perform functional programming. The term “React Hooks” refers to a type of function based on JavaScript which is used to isolate the functional component of a reusable function.\nBy using React, Hooks developers can use various react features without writing the classes which means we cannot write “use react hooks” in class components.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "34. What are the benefits of utilising React Js for front-end development? What is HOC in React Js?",
        "answer": "There are numerous reasons to prefer React Js over any other front-end development framework for the following reasons-\nReact Js offers better functionality and faster rendering of web pages.\nIt is a type of very flexible and stable framework, it also offers better testing and smooth development.\nComponents of React Js are highly usable and mainly focus on UI designs.\nReact Js is trusted by many tech giants and also it possesses very rich community support.\nReact Js is a very secure framework as it provides a unique data abstraction layer which prevents unnecessary code exposures to the users.\nHOC in React Js refers to Higher-Order Components which is a type of advanced method used by the developers for reusing the logic of a component’s functionality. It takes the previously developed original component and after processing it returns the enhanced results.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "35. How can we use clustering to enhance the performance of Node.Js?",
        "answer": "Clustering is an important concept in Node.Js, it enhances the performance of the Node.Js application, because Node.js apps operate on a single processor, they cannot make use of a multi-core machine by default. Cluster mode is used to launch numerous node.js processes, resulting in many event loop instances. When we use the cluster in a Node.Js app, many node.js processes are launched in the background, but there is also a parent process called the cluster manager that is in charge of monitoring the health of the individual instances of our application.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "36. What is Stub?",
        "answer": "Stubs in Node.Js refer to a type of small program regime which acts as dummy objects and can be used as substitutes for larger programs at the time of testing. These small programs affect the functionality and behavior of the various components and modules.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "37. Define Middleware. Mention all the types of Middleware in Express.Js",
        "answer": "Middleware is a type handler in Express.Js which is used to access the request-response cycle of the application. It acts as a function which holds the objects of request and response. After the server receives the request and before the controller actions transmit the response, middleware is invoked.\nVarious types of middleware in Express.Js are stated as –\nApplication Level Middleware\nRouter Level Middleware\nError Handling Middleware\nBuilt-inMiddleware\nThird-Party Middleware",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "38. What are Shards in MongoDB? Comment.",
        "answer": "A shard is a type of single instance in MongoDB which is used to hold the subset of sharded data. It can be brought into action as replica sets to provide data redundancy and increase the availability of the data. In MongoDB, a complete set is a combination of multiple shards. The process of distributing this type of data over multiple host locations is known as sharding. The concept of sharding in MongoDB is achieved by splitting up data into smaller modular instances.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "39. Explain in detail about DDL, DML, DCL, and TCL commands in SQL.",
        "answer": "Data Definition Language (DDL): It describes the data structure, which includes commands such as CREATE, ALTER, DROP, and so on.\nData Manipulation Language (DML): It is used to alter the database’s existing data. SELECT, UPDATE, INSERT, and other commands fall within this group.\nData Control Language (DCL): It governs access to the database’s data. GRANT and REVOKE are examples of commands in this category.\nTransaction Control Language (TCL): This language is used to manage database transactions. COMMIT, ROLLBACK, SET TRANSACTION, SAVEPOINT, and other commands fall within this group.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "40. Name various datatypes present in PostgreSQL.",
        "answer": "Various types of datatypes in PostgreSQL are as follows –\nNumeric types\nCharacter types\nTemporal types\nBoolean\nUUID\nGeometric primitives\nArbitrary precision numeric\nXML\nArrays etc.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "41. What is meant by a CSS Preprocessor? What are the terms Sass, Less, and Stylus mean? Why do people use them?",
        "answer": "CSS Preprocessor – A CSS Preprocessor is a tool that uses its programming language to extend the fundamental capabilities of vanilla CSS. It enables us to employ complicated logical constructs like variables, functions, mixins, code layering, and inheritance, to mention a few.\nSASS – SASS (Syntactically Awesome Style Sheets) is one of the CSS preprocessors which extends the functionality of CSS. It reduces the repetition of CSS statements.\nLESS – LESS (Leaner Stylesheets) is a CSS language extension that is backwards compatible. It enables us to use features such as variables, nesting, mixins, and so on in a CSS-compliant syntax. SASS has affected LESS, which has influenced SASS’s newer “SCSS” syntax.\nStylus: Stylus offers a high level of syntactic freedom, supports native CSS, and allows the elimination of brackets, colons, and semicolons. It does not define variables with @ or $.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "42. State the difference between Adaptive and Responsive designs.",
        "answer": "Here are the differences between Adaptive designs and Responsive design\nAdaptive Design Responsive Design\nAn adaptive design includes the production of a unique layout for each device on which the website will be browsed. A responsive design can alter its layout and look according to the screen size of the device being used to view it, which can range from a large desktop computer to a compact cellular device.\nA UX designer should produce up to six separate versions of a single website for different-sized displays when using adaptive design. While this is a lot of effort, it allows the UX designer to optimise the user experience for any device covered by these layouts. The responsive design generally requires less effort for a UX designer to produce, but they must collaborate with the developer to guarantee the site’s layout is useable at all screen sizes.\nSmaller sites that are being refreshed generally benefit the most from adaptive design. Responsive design works well for larger sites that are being built from the ground up.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "43. Comment on the boilerplate of an HTML document.",
        "answer": "When developing a new website, it is essential to have a solid foundational coding structure. A boilerplate code or simply a boilerplate is required for this foundation. In basic terms, they are parts of code that are repeated in several locations with minimal to no variation. A boilerplate in HTML is a template that you will include at the beginning of your project. This boilerplate should be included in all of your HTML pages.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "44. What is in HTML? Why do we use it? What are the differences that HTML-5 have with previous versions?",
        "answer": "in an HTML document refers to a type of declaration for the browser, which tells the browser that the present document is an HTML or XHTML document. Moreover, it also specifies the version of the HTML document in which the page is being written. is neither a tag nor an element, also it’s not case-sensitive and does not require a closing tag.\nSyntax of is as follows –",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "1. Explain the meaning of multithreading.",
        "answer": "The thread is an independent part or unit of a process (or an application) that is being executed. Whenever multiple threads execute in a process at the same time, we call this \"multithreading\". You can think of it as a way for an application to multitask.   Advantages: Advantages: By multithreading, computing resources are also minimized and used more effectively.\nThe response time of the application is improved since requests from one thread do not block requests from other threads.\nConsequently, if one of the threads encounters an exception, it will not affect the other threads.\nMultithreading, on the other hand, uses fewer resources than running multiple processes simultaneously.\nThe overhead, time usage, and management associated with creating processes are much higher when compared to creating and managing threads. By multithreading, computing resources are also minimized and used more effectively. The response time of the application is improved since requests from one thread do not block requests from other threads. Consequently, if one of the threads encounters an exception, it will not affect the other threads. Multithreading, on the other hand, uses fewer resources than running multiple processes simultaneously. The overhead, time usage, and management associated with creating processes are much higher when compared to creating and managing threads.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. Which language is the most preferred by full-stack developers?",
        "answer": "Full Stack Developers utilize several programming languages. Ideally, a candidate should be fluent in several languages, preferably some for designing the front end and others for fixing the back end. Since Full Stack developers work with a variety of technologies and applications, they must be proficient in at least two to three of the most popular languages such as Java, Python, Ruby, PHP, C++, etc. Java, Python, Ruby, PHP, C++, etc",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. Explain Pair Programming.",
        "answer": "In pair programming, two programmers share only one machine and work together. During the development process, one programmer will be the driver who codes and another will act as the observer (navigator) who will make sure the code is written correctly, proofread and spell-check it, while also deciding where to go next. Roles can be swapped at any time: the driver becomes the observer and vice versa. You can also call it \"pairing\", \"paired programming\", or \"programming in pairs\".   Advantages: Advantages: Two of them will fix the problem if the driver encounters any issues with the code.\nThe two programmers working on the same program are only 15% slower than if they worked independently instead of 50%.\nAs a result of having another programmer look over your work, you are more likely to write better code. One study showed that it results in 15% fewer bugs than code written by a single programmer.\nIt leads to improved collaboration, higher quality, better code, and sustained improved development practices.\nDuring the project, each person teaches the other, resulting in more efficient and expedited knowledge exchange.\nThe team develops better communication skills. Two of them will fix the problem if the driver encounters any issues with the code. The two programmers working on the same program are only 15% slower than if they worked independently instead of 50%. As a result of having another programmer look over your work, you are more likely to write better code. One study showed that it results in 15% fewer bugs than code written by a single programmer. It leads to improved collaboration, higher quality, better code, and sustained improved development practices. During the project, each person teaches the other, resulting in more efficient and expedited knowledge exchange. The team develops better communication skills.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. What do you mean by CORS (Cross-Origin Resource Sharing)?",
        "answer": "CORS refers to cross-origin resource sharing. It's a browser mechanism that allows web pages in one domain to have controlled access to resources in other domains (cross-domain requests). This allows scripts that are run on a browser client to interact with and access resources from other origins. In doing so, it extends and provides greater flexibility to the SOP (Same-Origin Policy). Same-origin policies restrict the ability of a website to access resources outside of its source domain. For example, a JavaScript app that wants to make a call to an API (Application Programming Interface) that runs on another domain will be blocked due to the SOP. A CORS policy was implemented to circumvent restrictions caused by same-origin policies.   In addition, if a website's CORS policy is not configured properly, it may be vulnerable to cross-domain attacks. This means that it cannot stop cross-origin attacks like  CSRF (Cross-Site Request Forgery).",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. What is Callback Hell?",
        "answer": "Callback Hell, or Pyramid of Doom, is a common anti-pattern seen in asynchronous programming code (multiple functions running at the same time). This slang term describes a large number of nested \"if\" statements or functions. In simple terms, Callback hell is a situation where you have multiple asynchronous functions. Those functions depend on one another, so it could get quite messy with so many callback functions nested in so many layers. The use of callback functions leaves you with code that is difficult to read and maintain, and looks like a pyramid as shown below: This also makes it more difficult to identify the flow of the application, which is the main obstacle to debugging, which is the reason for the famous name of this problem: Callback Hell.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. Explain Long Polling.",
        "answer": "Long polling is defined as a web application development technique used to push information/data from servers to clients as quickly as possible. When a request is made from the client to the server, long-polling maintains the connection between the two. This connection is maintained until the information is ready to be sent from the server to the client.  Once a server receives a request from a client, the connection does not close immediately; the connection is only closed once the server has sent the data back to the client or when a timeout threshold has been reached (connection timeout).  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. Can you tell me what are the latest trends in Full Stack Development? Also, how do you keep yourself updated about the new trends in the industry?",
        "answer": "Each business needs emerging technology to thrive, whether it is mobile or web application development. This is why they hire front-end developers, back-end developers, or full-stack developers depending on their technology needs. According to industry experts, candidates who are passionate about full-stack development should be aware of these trends: back-end developers The rise in frameworks and libraries like ReacJs and VueJs, progressive apps,  real-time web apps, and mobile web development.\nEnhancements to JavaScript are beneficial to programming\nThe emergence of a more compatible extension. The rise in frameworks and libraries like ReacJs and VueJs, progressive apps,  real-time web apps, and mobile web development. Enhancements to JavaScript are beneficial to programming The emergence of a more compatible extension. The interviewer may ask you how you keep updated with new trends in the industry. You can explain how you gain your knowledge and understanding by learning from friends, colleagues, or online. That's an appropriate way of answering the question. This is a good time to show off any personal projects you have undertaken that apply your skills. Also, you might mention the webinars or forums that you attend regularly.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. State difference between GraphQL and REST (Representational State Transfer).",
        "answer": "For decades, REST (Representational State Transfer) has been a popular architectural way to design APIs (Application Programming Interfaces), but the popularity of GraphQL over the past few years threatens to topple REST. In general, REST and GraphQL both aim to transfer data over internet protocols including HTTP. How they do so differs greatly, however.   GraphQL REST\nIt is a Query Language for APIs that enables declarative data fetching to provide clients control over which data to retrieve from the API.  It is an API design architectural style that defines a set of constraints to create web services.\nGraphQL is known for its high predictability. With this, you can send requests to your API and get the exact results you are looking for without having to include anything you don't need. GraphQL queries give predictable results, which improves their usability significantly. On the other hand, REST's behaviour depends on the HTTP and URI methods used. API consumers can therefore be unsure of what to expect when calling an endpoint.\nAPI security can be ensured by GraphQL, though the security features aren't as mature as those of REST. GraphQL, for instance, assists in integrating data validation, but users are left to figure out how to apply authentication and authorization measures. API security can be enforced in several ways using REST. You can implement multiple methods of API authentication, such as HTTP authentication, to ensure REST API security.\nWith GraphQL, you can retrieve everything you need through a single API request. You can specify the structure of the information you need, and the server will return the same structure to you, so there is no need to over-and under-fetch. Consequently, since REST APIs have rigid data structures that return the specified data whenever they are accessed, you may end up with unwanted data or have to make multiple requests before getting the right data. As a result, the server's response time (to return information) can be prolonged due to these shortcomings.\nIt only supports JSON format. XML, YAML, JSON, HTML, and other formats are supported, as well.\nThe main use cases of GraphQL are mobile applications and multiple microservices. Rest is mainly used for simple applications and resource-driven applications. GraphQL REST\nIt is a Query Language for APIs that enables declarative data fetching to provide clients control over which data to retrieve from the API.  It is an API design architectural style that defines a set of constraints to create web services.\nGraphQL is known for its high predictability. With this, you can send requests to your API and get the exact results you are looking for without having to include anything you don't need. GraphQL queries give predictable results, which improves their usability significantly. On the other hand, REST's behaviour depends on the HTTP and URI methods used. API consumers can therefore be unsure of what to expect when calling an endpoint.\nAPI security can be ensured by GraphQL, though the security features aren't as mature as those of REST. GraphQL, for instance, assists in integrating data validation, but users are left to figure out how to apply authentication and authorization measures. API security can be enforced in several ways using REST. You can implement multiple methods of API authentication, such as HTTP authentication, to ensure REST API security.\nWith GraphQL, you can retrieve everything you need through a single API request. You can specify the structure of the information you need, and the server will return the same structure to you, so there is no need to over-and under-fetch. Consequently, since REST APIs have rigid data structures that return the specified data whenever they are accessed, you may end up with unwanted data or have to make multiple requests before getting the right data. As a result, the server's response time (to return information) can be prolonged due to these shortcomings.\nIt only supports JSON format. XML, YAML, JSON, HTML, and other formats are supported, as well.\nThe main use cases of GraphQL are mobile applications and multiple microservices. Rest is mainly used for simple applications and resource-driven applications. GraphQL REST GraphQL REST GraphQL REST It is a Query Language for APIs that enables declarative data fetching to provide clients control over which data to retrieve from the API.  It is an API design architectural style that defines a set of constraints to create web services.\nGraphQL is known for its high predictability. With this, you can send requests to your API and get the exact results you are looking for without having to include anything you don't need. GraphQL queries give predictable results, which improves their usability significantly. On the other hand, REST's behaviour depends on the HTTP and URI methods used. API consumers can therefore be unsure of what to expect when calling an endpoint.\nAPI security can be ensured by GraphQL, though the security features aren't as mature as those of REST. GraphQL, for instance, assists in integrating data validation, but users are left to figure out how to apply authentication and authorization measures. API security can be enforced in several ways using REST. You can implement multiple methods of API authentication, such as HTTP authentication, to ensure REST API security.\nWith GraphQL, you can retrieve everything you need through a single API request. You can specify the structure of the information you need, and the server will return the same structure to you, so there is no need to over-and under-fetch. Consequently, since REST APIs have rigid data structures that return the specified data whenever they are accessed, you may end up with unwanted data or have to make multiple requests before getting the right data. As a result, the server's response time (to return information) can be prolonged due to these shortcomings.\nIt only supports JSON format. XML, YAML, JSON, HTML, and other formats are supported, as well.\nThe main use cases of GraphQL are mobile applications and multiple microservices. Rest is mainly used for simple applications and resource-driven applications. It is a Query Language for APIs that enables declarative data fetching to provide clients control over which data to retrieve from the API.  It is an API design architectural style that defines a set of constraints to create web services. It is a Query Language for APIs that enables declarative data fetching to provide clients control over which data to retrieve from the API. It is an API design architectural style that defines a set of constraints to create web services. GraphQL is known for its high predictability. With this, you can send requests to your API and get the exact results you are looking for without having to include anything you don't need. GraphQL queries give predictable results, which improves their usability significantly. On the other hand, REST's behaviour depends on the HTTP and URI methods used. API consumers can therefore be unsure of what to expect when calling an endpoint. GraphQL is known for its high predictability. With this, you can send requests to your API and get the exact results you are looking for without having to include anything you don't need. GraphQL queries give predictable results, which improves their usability significantly. On the other hand, REST's behaviour depends on the HTTP and URI methods used. API consumers can therefore be unsure of what to expect when calling an endpoint. API security can be ensured by GraphQL, though the security features aren't as mature as those of REST. GraphQL, for instance, assists in integrating data validation, but users are left to figure out how to apply authentication and authorization measures. API security can be enforced in several ways using REST. You can implement multiple methods of API authentication, such as HTTP authentication, to ensure REST API security. API security can be ensured by GraphQL, though the security features aren't as mature as those of REST. GraphQL, for instance, assists in integrating data validation, but users are left to figure out how to apply authentication and authorization measures. API security can be enforced in several ways using REST. You can implement multiple methods of API authentication, such as HTTP authentication, to ensure REST API security. With GraphQL, you can retrieve everything you need through a single API request. You can specify the structure of the information you need, and the server will return the same structure to you, so there is no need to over-and under-fetch. Consequently, since REST APIs have rigid data structures that return the specified data whenever they are accessed, you may end up with unwanted data or have to make multiple requests before getting the right data. As a result, the server's response time (to return information) can be prolonged due to these shortcomings. With GraphQL, you can retrieve everything you need through a single API request. You can specify the structure of the information you need, and the server will return the same structure to you, so there is no need to over-and under-fetch. Consequently, since REST APIs have rigid data structures that return the specified data whenever they are accessed, you may end up with unwanted data or have to make multiple requests before getting the right data. As a result, the server's response time (to return information) can be prolonged due to these shortcomings. It only supports JSON format. XML, YAML, JSON, HTML, and other formats are supported, as well. It only supports JSON format. XML, YAML, JSON, HTML, and other formats are supported, as well. The main use cases of GraphQL are mobile applications and multiple microservices. Rest is mainly used for simple applications and resource-driven applications. The main use cases of GraphQL are mobile applications and multiple microservices. Rest is mainly used for simple applications and resource-driven applications.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. What is CI (Continuous Integration)?",
        "answer": "CI (Continuous Integration), as its name implies, is the process of automating and integrating code changes into a single software project, often several times a day. The purpose of this DevOps practice is to enable developers to merge their code changes into a central repository where automated tests and builds can run. Automated tools are used to assert the new code’s correctness before integration. A source code version control system is the crux of the CI process. The version control system is also supplemented with other checks like automated code quality tests, syntax style review tools, and more.   Advantages: Advantages: Integrating regularly has the main benefit of detecting errors quickly and more easily. Since most changes introduced are small, pinpointing the specific change that caused a defect is easy.\nAs a result of the smaller code changes and easier fault isolations, CI reduces MTTR (Mean Time to Resolution).\nWhen CI is incorporated into your organization's development process, you are less likely to have noncritical defects on your backlog. Before production, these small defects are detected and fixed before they are released to the public. Integrating regularly has the main benefit of detecting errors quickly and more easily. Since most changes introduced are small, pinpointing the specific change that caused a defect is easy. As a result of the smaller code changes and easier fault isolations, CI reduces MTTR (Mean Time to Resolution). When CI is incorporated into your organization's development process, you are less likely to have noncritical defects on your backlog. Before production, these small defects are detected and fixed before they are released to the public.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. To develop a project from scratch, what technologies and languages would you need or what skills a full stack developer should have?",
        "answer": "A full-stack developer must be familiar with the following: full-stack developer full-stack developer Programming Languages: Full-stack developers should be competent in more than one programming language, such as Java, Python, PHP, Ruby, C++, etc.\nFront End technologies: You should be familiar with front-end technologies such as HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, etc. Knowledge of third-party libraries such as jQuery, Ajax, Angular, ReactJS, etc., is also important.\nFrameworks: This requires proficiency in a variety of development frameworks, including Spring, Spring Boot, Django, MyBatis, PHP, Hibernate, and others.\nDatabases and caches: As a full stack developer, you should also know about various DBMS (Database Management Systems) technologies like MySQL, SQLite, Oracle, and MongoDB. It is helpful to have a basic understanding of caching mechanisms like redis, memcached, varnish.\nDesign Ability: Having a good understanding of design is also important if you wish to become a successful Full-Stack web developer. Moreover, the person should be aware of the principles of prototyping and UX/UI design.\nServer: Experience with Apache or NGINX would be beneficial. Good knowledge of Linux helps enormously when administering servers. Programming Languages: Full-stack developers should be competent in more than one programming language, such as Java, Python, PHP, Ruby, C++, etc. Programming Languages: Front End technologies: You should be familiar with front-end technologies such as HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, etc. Knowledge of third-party libraries such as jQuery, Ajax, Angular, ReactJS, etc., is also important. Front End technologies: Frameworks: This requires proficiency in a variety of development frameworks, including Spring, Spring Boot, Django, MyBatis, PHP, Hibernate, and others. Frameworks: Databases and caches: As a full stack developer, you should also know about various DBMS (Database Management Systems) technologies like MySQL, SQLite, Oracle, and MongoDB. It is helpful to have a basic understanding of caching mechanisms like redis, memcached, varnish. Databases and caches: Design Ability: Having a good understanding of design is also important if you wish to become a successful Full-Stack web developer. Moreover, the person should be aware of the principles of prototyping and UX/UI design. Design Ability: Server: Experience with Apache or NGINX would be beneficial. Good knowledge of Linux helps enormously when administering servers. Server:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. Explain the benefits and drawbacks of using \"use strict\".",
        "answer": "In ECMAScript5, a new feature known as strict mode allows you to run a program or function within a strict operating context. Certain actions, therefore, cannot be taken due to this strict context, and more exceptions are thrown. When the \"use strict\" statement is used, the browser is instructed to use \"strict\" mode, which is a more restricted and safer JavaScript feature set. You can specify \"use strict\" at the top of a function to evaluate the JS in strict mode. In strict mode, more errors are thrown and some features are disabled to make your code more robust, clear, and accurate.   Advantages: Advantages: Errors are thrown when some common coding mistakes are detected.\nBy having strict mode, mistakes that make JavaScript engines tough to optimize can be fixed. Sometimes, strict mode code runs faster than similar, non-strict mode code.\nGenerally, it prevents or throws an error when an \"unsafe\" action is taken (for example, accessing the global object).\nIt disables poorly thought-out or confusing features.\nStrict mode simplifies the process of writing \"secure\" JavaScript. Errors are thrown when some common coding mistakes are detected. By having strict mode, mistakes that make JavaScript engines tough to optimize can be fixed. Sometimes, strict mode code runs faster than similar, non-strict mode code. Generally, it prevents or throws an error when an \"unsafe\" action is taken (for example, accessing the global object). It disables poorly thought-out or confusing features. Strict mode simplifies the process of writing \"secure\" JavaScript. Disadvantages: Disadvantages: Many of the functions that most developers use are absent.\nIt is not possible to access function.caller or function.arguments anymore.\nIf you concatenate scripts written in different strict modes, you may encounter problems. Many of the functions that most developers use are absent. It is not possible to access function.caller or function.arguments anymore. If you concatenate scripts written in different strict modes, you may encounter problems.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "12. What are some of the uses of Docker?",
        "answer": "One of the thorniest problems in software development is dealing with the different environments across different machines and platforms. Using Docker, you can isolate your applications from your infrastructure, which is crucial to delivering software quickly. Developers can package and run their applications into containers, executable components that have all the OS (Operating System) libraries and dependencies needed to run the application in any environment. It does not matter what is installed on the host—containers are lightweight and include everything needed to run applications. The code has to pass through many different environments as it travels from the developer's machine to production. Consequently, each of these environments may be slightly different. Using Docker streamlines code development and deployment, as it provides a consistent environment from development to production.\nDocker's primary purpose is to simplify configuration. With VM (Virtual Machine), you can run any platform with its configuration on top of your infrastructure. Docker offers the same functionality without the overhead of virtual machines. The code has to pass through many different environments as it travels from the developer's machine to production. Consequently, each of these environments may be slightly different. Using Docker streamlines code development and deployment, as it provides a consistent environment from development to production. Docker's primary purpose is to simplify configuration. With VM (Virtual Machine), you can run any platform with its configuration on top of your infrastructure. Docker offers the same functionality without the overhead of virtual machines.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "13. Explain event loop in Node.js.",
        "answer": "The event loop in JavaScript enables asynchronous programming. With JS, every operation takes place on a single thread, but through smart data structures, we can create the illusion of multi-threading. With the Event Loop, any async work is handled by a queue and listener. Consider the diagram below:   Therefore, when an async function (or an I/O) needs to be executed, the main thread relays it to another thread, allowing v8 (Javascript engine) to continue processing or running its code. In the event loop, there are different phases, like pending callbacks, closing callbacks, timers, idle or preparing, polling, and checking, with different FIFO (First-In-First-Out) queues.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "14. Is there a way to decrease the load time of a web application?",
        "answer": "Here are some ways to reduce load times for web applications: Image Optimization: The file size of an image can be dramatically reduced by switching to a different file format. For example, GIFs work well for images with few colors, such as logos, JPEG is ideal for images with lots of colors and details, such as photographs, and PNG format is ideal for transparent images with high quality.\nKeep JavaScript and CSS in external files: Embedding JavaScript and CSS in HTML documents forces them to be downloaded every time the HTML document is loaded. In this case, browser caching is not utilized, and the HTML document becomes larger. This is why you should always place CSS and JavaScript in external files; it is a best practice and simplifies maintenance.\nReducing redirects: Too many redirects will delay the loading time of a website. HTTP requests and responses are delayed each time a page redirects. Getting rid of unnecessary redirects on your site will reduce the load time of your site significantly.\nLoad CSS and JavaScript files asynchronously: Your website contains CSS and JavaScript files that can be loaded either synchronously or asynchronously. As part of synchronous loading, each file is loaded sequentially, in the order it appears on your site. As opposed to synchronous loading, asynchronous loading allows multiple files to be loaded simultaneously, boosting the performance of a website. \nMinify HTML, CSS, and JavaScript: If you optimize the way your files load, your pages will load more quickly. You can do the same when it comes to HTML, CSS, and JavaScript code. By eliminating unnecessary spaces, characters, and comments, you can reduce the size of your files. This will make your web pages load faster. Image Optimization: The file size of an image can be dramatically reduced by switching to a different file format. For example, GIFs work well for images with few colors, such as logos, JPEG is ideal for images with lots of colors and details, such as photographs, and PNG format is ideal for transparent images with high quality. Image Optimization: Keep JavaScript and CSS in external files: Embedding JavaScript and CSS in HTML documents forces them to be downloaded every time the HTML document is loaded. In this case, browser caching is not utilized, and the HTML document becomes larger. This is why you should always place CSS and JavaScript in external files; it is a best practice and simplifies maintenance. Keep JavaScript and CSS in external files: Reducing redirects: Too many redirects will delay the loading time of a website. HTTP requests and responses are delayed each time a page redirects. Getting rid of unnecessary redirects on your site will reduce the load time of your site significantly. Reducing redirects: Load CSS and JavaScript files asynchronously: Your website contains CSS and JavaScript files that can be loaded either synchronously or asynchronously. As part of synchronous loading, each file is loaded sequentially, in the order it appears on your site. As opposed to synchronous loading, asynchronous loading allows multiple files to be loaded simultaneously, boosting the performance of a website. Load CSS and JavaScript files asynchronously: Minify HTML, CSS, and JavaScript: If you optimize the way your files load, your pages will load more quickly. You can do the same when it comes to HTML, CSS, and JavaScript code. By eliminating unnecessary spaces, characters, and comments, you can reduce the size of your files. This will make your web pages load faster. Minify HTML, CSS, and JavaScript:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "15. Explain dependency injection.",
        "answer": "The Dependency Injection (DI) pattern is a design pattern for implementing the Inversion of Control (IoC). Dependent objects can be created outside of classes and made available to classes in different ways. Three types of classes are involved in Dependency Injection as follows:   Client Class: A client class (dependent class) is one that depends on the service class.\nService Class: Service (dependency) classes provide services to client classes.\nInjector Class: This class injects the objects from the service class into the client class. Client Class: A client class (dependent class) is one that depends on the service class. Service Class: Service (dependency) classes provide services to client classes. Injector Class: This class injects the objects from the service class into the client class.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "16. What do you mean by observer pattern?",
        "answer": "If several objects are tied together in one-to-many relationships, the observer pattern is used. Every time one object is modified, then all of its dependent objects are automatically notified and updated. It falls under the behavioural pattern category. It describes the coupling between the objects and the observer and provides support for broadcast-type communication. The object that observes the state of another object is known as the observer, and the object that is being observed is known as the subject as shown below:  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "1. Why should arrow functions not be used in ES6?",
        "answer": "One of the most popular features of ES6 is the \"arrow functions\" (also known as \"fat arrow functions\"). Arrow functions are a new way to write concise functions. Arrow functions offer a compact alternative to traditional function expressions, but they have limitations and cannot be used in every case. The following is an ES5 function: function timesTwo(params) {\n        return params * 2\n     }\ntimesTwo(5);  // 10 function timesTwo(params) {\n        return params * 2\n     }\ntimesTwo(5);  // 10 The same function can also be expressed as an arrow function in ES6 as follows: var timesTwo = params => params * 2\ntimesTwo(5);  // 10 var timesTwo = params => params * 2\ntimesTwo(5);  // 10 Differences & Limitations: Differences & Limitations: Has no bindings to 'this' or 'super', so it shouldn't be used as a method.\nHas no new.target keyword.\nThe call, apply, and bind methods are not suitable since they rely on establishing scope.\nNot suitable for use as constructors.\nNot possible for an arrow function to use the yield keyword within its body, etc. Has no bindings to 'this' or 'super', so it shouldn't be used as a method. Has no new.target keyword. The call, apply, and bind methods are not suitable since they rely on establishing scope. Not suitable for use as constructors. Not possible for an arrow function to use the yield keyword within its body, etc.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. State difference between normalization and denormalization.",
        "answer": "Normalization and denormalization are the two main methods of altering the structure of a database.   Normalization Denormalization\nNormalization involves removing redundant data (multiple copies of data) from a database and storing consistent, non-redundant data. It involves combining data from multiple tables into a single so that it can be queried quickly.\nIt primarily focuses on clearing out unused data and reducing duplicate data and inconsistencies from a database. On the other hand, denormalization aims to achieve faster query execution by adding data redundancy.\nDuring normalization, tables are reduced in number due to the reduction of data in the database. Denormalization, on the other hand, involves integrating data into the same database and therefore the number of tables to store the data increases.\nData integrity is maintained by normalization. A change to the data in the table will not impact its relationship with the other table. Data integrity is not maintained by denormalization.\nIt optimizes the use of disk space. It does not optimize disk space. Normalization Denormalization\nNormalization involves removing redundant data (multiple copies of data) from a database and storing consistent, non-redundant data. It involves combining data from multiple tables into a single so that it can be queried quickly.\nIt primarily focuses on clearing out unused data and reducing duplicate data and inconsistencies from a database. On the other hand, denormalization aims to achieve faster query execution by adding data redundancy.\nDuring normalization, tables are reduced in number due to the reduction of data in the database. Denormalization, on the other hand, involves integrating data into the same database and therefore the number of tables to store the data increases.\nData integrity is maintained by normalization. A change to the data in the table will not impact its relationship with the other table. Data integrity is not maintained by denormalization.\nIt optimizes the use of disk space. It does not optimize disk space. Normalization Denormalization Normalization Denormalization Normalization Denormalization Normalization involves removing redundant data (multiple copies of data) from a database and storing consistent, non-redundant data. It involves combining data from multiple tables into a single so that it can be queried quickly.\nIt primarily focuses on clearing out unused data and reducing duplicate data and inconsistencies from a database. On the other hand, denormalization aims to achieve faster query execution by adding data redundancy.\nDuring normalization, tables are reduced in number due to the reduction of data in the database. Denormalization, on the other hand, involves integrating data into the same database and therefore the number of tables to store the data increases.\nData integrity is maintained by normalization. A change to the data in the table will not impact its relationship with the other table. Data integrity is not maintained by denormalization.\nIt optimizes the use of disk space. It does not optimize disk space. Normalization involves removing redundant data (multiple copies of data) from a database and storing consistent, non-redundant data. It involves combining data from multiple tables into a single so that it can be queried quickly. Normalization involves removing redundant data (multiple copies of data) from a database and storing consistent, non-redundant data. It involves combining data from multiple tables into a single so that it can be queried quickly. It primarily focuses on clearing out unused data and reducing duplicate data and inconsistencies from a database. On the other hand, denormalization aims to achieve faster query execution by adding data redundancy. It primarily focuses on clearing out unused data and reducing duplicate data and inconsistencies from a database. On the other hand, denormalization aims to achieve faster query execution by adding data redundancy. During normalization, tables are reduced in number due to the reduction of data in the database. Denormalization, on the other hand, involves integrating data into the same database and therefore the number of tables to store the data increases. During normalization, tables are reduced in number due to the reduction of data in the database. Denormalization, on the other hand, involves integrating data into the same database and therefore the number of tables to store the data increases. Data integrity is maintained by normalization. A change to the data in the table will not impact its relationship with the other table. Data integrity is not maintained by denormalization. Data integrity is maintained by normalization. A change to the data in the table will not impact its relationship with the other table. Data integrity is not maintained by denormalization. It optimizes the use of disk space. It does not optimize disk space. It optimizes the use of disk space. It does not optimize disk space.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. In Java, what is a connection leak? How can you fix this?",
        "answer": "If a connection is opened and forgotten about, this is known as a \"leak\" since each time it occurs, a connection is no longer available for reuse. Connection leaks occur when some database requests or transactions are not closed properly or are not committed, causing the connections to be abandoned and closed permanently. Java developers commonly experience Connection Leaks when using Connection Pools. In the case where there is a section of code that fails to close a connection properly, a connection will leak from the pool each time the section of code is executed. Eventually, if this situation continues, the pool will run out of connections, which is known as Pool Exhaustion. The application will hang once all available connections have been leaked. We can fix this by closing the connection and paying particular attention to any error handling code.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. What is Promise and explain its states?",
        "answer": "Callback functions are functions that can be passed to another function as arguments and executed there to complete a routine or action. Those functions depend on one another, so it could get quite messy with so many callback functions nested in so many layers. This is what is referred to as callback hell. As an alternative to callbacks in JavaScript, promises are used to handle asynchronous operations. In addition to handling multiple asynchronous operations, they provide better error handling than callbacks. Promises can be a better way for a user to read the code effectively and efficiently, especially when that particular code performs multiple asynchronous operations. The Promise object represents the result of an asynchronous operation (or its failure) and the resulting value. The promise is in one of the following states: Pending: In its initial state, neither fulfilled nor rejected.\nFulfilled: Indicating that the operation was successful.\nRejected: Indicating that the operation failed. Pending: In its initial state, neither fulfilled nor rejected. Pending: Fulfilled: Indicating that the operation was successful. Fulfilled: Rejected: Indicating that the operation failed. Rejected:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. State the difference between GET and POST.",
        "answer": "GET and POST are two different HTTP request methods. GET POST\nThis method is used to request data from a certain resource (via some API URL). This method is used to send or write data to be processed to a specific resource (via some API URL).\nIf you use the GET method to send data, the data is added to the URL, and a URL can be up to 2048 characters in length. Therefore, it has restrictions on data length. It does not impose such limitations.\nIn comparison to POST, GET is less secure since data is sent as part of the URL. Passwords and other sensitive information should never be sent using GET. It is a little safer to use POST than GET because the parameters are not saved in the browser history or the web server logs.\nEveryone can see the data in the URL. There is no data displayed in the URL. GET POST\nThis method is used to request data from a certain resource (via some API URL). This method is used to send or write data to be processed to a specific resource (via some API URL).\nIf you use the GET method to send data, the data is added to the URL, and a URL can be up to 2048 characters in length. Therefore, it has restrictions on data length. It does not impose such limitations.\nIn comparison to POST, GET is less secure since data is sent as part of the URL. Passwords and other sensitive information should never be sent using GET. It is a little safer to use POST than GET because the parameters are not saved in the browser history or the web server logs.\nEveryone can see the data in the URL. There is no data displayed in the URL. GET POST GET POST GET POST This method is used to request data from a certain resource (via some API URL). This method is used to send or write data to be processed to a specific resource (via some API URL).\nIf you use the GET method to send data, the data is added to the URL, and a URL can be up to 2048 characters in length. Therefore, it has restrictions on data length. It does not impose such limitations.\nIn comparison to POST, GET is less secure since data is sent as part of the URL. Passwords and other sensitive information should never be sent using GET. It is a little safer to use POST than GET because the parameters are not saved in the browser history or the web server logs.\nEveryone can see the data in the URL. There is no data displayed in the URL. This method is used to request data from a certain resource (via some API URL). This method is used to send or write data to be processed to a specific resource (via some API URL). This method is used to request data from a certain resource (via some API URL). This method is used to send or write data to be processed to a specific resource (via some API URL). If you use the GET method to send data, the data is added to the URL, and a URL can be up to 2048 characters in length. Therefore, it has restrictions on data length. It does not impose such limitations. If you use the GET method to send data, the data is added to the URL, and a URL can be up to 2048 characters in length. Therefore, it has restrictions on data length. It does not impose such limitations. In comparison to POST, GET is less secure since data is sent as part of the URL. Passwords and other sensitive information should never be sent using GET. It is a little safer to use POST than GET because the parameters are not saved in the browser history or the web server logs. In comparison to POST, GET is less secure since data is sent as part of the URL. Passwords and other sensitive information should never be sent using GET. It is a little safer to use POST than GET because the parameters are not saved in the browser history or the web server logs. Everyone can see the data in the URL. There is no data displayed in the URL. Everyone can see the data in the URL. There is no data displayed in the URL.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. Explain the Restful API and write its usage.",
        "answer": "APIs (Application Programming Interfaces) are sets of rules and protocols that define how software programs or devices can communicate with each other. APIs that conform to the design principles of REST, or representational state transfer, are known as REST APIs. REST APIs may also be referred to as RESTful APIs. Using RESTful APIs, developers can create requests and receive responses via an HTTP request. REST API can also be used for mapping data from a cloud platform to a data warehouse or vice versa.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. What do you mean by MEAN Stack?",
        "answer": "MEAN stands for MongoDB, ExpressJS, AngularJS, and Node.js. It is a collection of JavaScript-based technologies for developing web applications. Despite being a stack of different technologies, all of them are based on the JavaScript language. It is an ideal solution for building dynamic websites and applications as it is a very user-friendly stack. With this free and open-source stack, you can quickly and easily build web-based prototypes.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. Do you know how to prevent a bot from scraping your publicly accessible API?",
        "answer": "As long as the data within the API is accessible to the public, it will technically not be possible to completely prevent data scraping. It is possible, however, to minimize bot activity (automated computer programs on the internet that perform certain tasks) by throttling or rare limiting. Rare limiting will be able to prevent a certain device from making an unlimited number of requests within a defined time. If too many requests are made beyond the defined limit, a 429 Too Many Attempts HTTP error is thrown. It is vital to record more than just the IP address of the device since the IP address is not unique to each device and can stop the whole network from accessing the API.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. What makes MVC (Model View Controller) different from MVP (Model View Presenter)?",
        "answer": "Developers prefer to develop Android applications by utilizing a software architecture pattern. Architecture patterns allow you to express and define a structural schema for software systems. Developers can easily maintain the software and continue to add features to the software in the future. The two most popular android architecture patterns are MVC (Model View Controller) and MVP (Model View Presenter). MVC MVP\nMVC suggests splitting the code into three components. As soon as the developer creates a class or file for an application, he or she must categorize it into one of three layers: Model, View, and Controller. This is an architectural pattern that helps compensate for some of the shortcomings of MVC. It is composed of three components i.e., Model, View, and Presenter.\nThe controller serves as a bridge between the view and model layers and therefore provides the application's user interface. As soon as the Model changes, the Controller updates the View. The presenter pulls data from the model and applies the UI  (user interface) logic to determine what to show. In response to the user's input notification, it manages the state of the View and takes appropriate actions.\nControllers and views have a many-to-one relationship since one Controller can select different Views depending on the operation required. Presenter and View have a one-to-one relationship since the Presenter class manages only one View at a time.\nSupport for unit testing is limited.  The unit testing process is highly supported. MVC MVP\nMVC suggests splitting the code into three components. As soon as the developer creates a class or file for an application, he or she must categorize it into one of three layers: Model, View, and Controller. This is an architectural pattern that helps compensate for some of the shortcomings of MVC. It is composed of three components i.e., Model, View, and Presenter.\nThe controller serves as a bridge between the view and model layers and therefore provides the application's user interface. As soon as the Model changes, the Controller updates the View. The presenter pulls data from the model and applies the UI  (user interface) logic to determine what to show. In response to the user's input notification, it manages the state of the View and takes appropriate actions.\nControllers and views have a many-to-one relationship since one Controller can select different Views depending on the operation required. Presenter and View have a one-to-one relationship since the Presenter class manages only one View at a time.\nSupport for unit testing is limited.  The unit testing process is highly supported. MVC MVP MVC MVP MVC MVP MVC suggests splitting the code into three components. As soon as the developer creates a class or file for an application, he or she must categorize it into one of three layers: Model, View, and Controller. This is an architectural pattern that helps compensate for some of the shortcomings of MVC. It is composed of three components i.e., Model, View, and Presenter.\nThe controller serves as a bridge between the view and model layers and therefore provides the application's user interface. As soon as the Model changes, the Controller updates the View. The presenter pulls data from the model and applies the UI  (user interface) logic to determine what to show. In response to the user's input notification, it manages the state of the View and takes appropriate actions.\nControllers and views have a many-to-one relationship since one Controller can select different Views depending on the operation required. Presenter and View have a one-to-one relationship since the Presenter class manages only one View at a time.\nSupport for unit testing is limited.  The unit testing process is highly supported. MVC suggests splitting the code into three components. As soon as the developer creates a class or file for an application, he or she must categorize it into one of three layers: Model, View, and Controller. This is an architectural pattern that helps compensate for some of the shortcomings of MVC. It is composed of three components i.e., Model, View, and Presenter. MVC suggests splitting the code into three components. As soon as the developer creates a class or file for an application, he or she must categorize it into one of three layers: Model, View, and Controller. This is an architectural pattern that helps compensate for some of the shortcomings of MVC. It is composed of three components i.e., Model, View, and Presenter. The controller serves as a bridge between the view and model layers and therefore provides the application's user interface. As soon as the Model changes, the Controller updates the View. The presenter pulls data from the model and applies the UI  (user interface) logic to determine what to show. In response to the user's input notification, it manages the state of the View and takes appropriate actions. The controller serves as a bridge between the view and model layers and therefore provides the application's user interface. As soon as the Model changes, the Controller updates the View. The presenter pulls data from the model and applies the UI  (user interface) logic to determine what to show. In response to the user's input notification, it manages the state of the View and takes appropriate actions. Controllers and views have a many-to-one relationship since one Controller can select different Views depending on the operation required. Presenter and View have a one-to-one relationship since the Presenter class manages only one View at a time. Controllers and views have a many-to-one relationship since one Controller can select different Views depending on the operation required. Presenter and View have a one-to-one relationship since the Presenter class manages only one View at a time. Support for unit testing is limited.  The unit testing process is highly supported. Support for unit testing is limited. The unit testing process is highly supported.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. What do you mean by Temporal Dead Zone in ES6?",
        "answer": "Before ES6, variable declarations were only possible using var. With ES6, we got let and const. Both let and const declarations are block-scoped, i.e., they can only be accessed within the \" { } \" surrounding them. On the other hand, var doesn't have such a restriction. Unlike var, which can be accessed before its declaration, you cannot access the let or const variables until they are initialized with some value. Temporal Dead Zone is the time from the beginning of the execution of a block in which let or const variables are declared until these variables are initialized. If anyone tries to access those variables during that zone, Javascript will always throw a reference error as given below. console.log(varNumber); // undefined\nconsole.log(letNumber); // Throws the reference error letNumber is not defined\nvar varNumber = 3;\nlet letNumber = 4; console.log(varNumber); // undefined\nconsole.log(letNumber); // Throws the reference error letNumber is not defined\nvar varNumber = 3;\nlet letNumber = 4; Both let and const variables are in the TDZ from the moment their enclosing scope starts to the moment they are declared.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. What do you mean by referential transparency in functional programming?",
        "answer": "In functional programming, referential transparency is the key differentiating factor.  An expression is considered referential transparent if it can be replaced or substituted with the corresponding value it computes or vice-versa without affecting the program’s result. Example: Imagine that we have an expression called four: val four= add(1,3) Example: Example: val four= add(1,3) If four is used anywhere in our code, it can safely be replaced with add(1,3), 1 + 3 or 4 wherever it appears. Thus, all the expressions below are equivalent in meaning and output: val eight = four + four\nval eight_v2 = add(1,3) + add(1,3)\nval eight_v3 = 4 + add(1,3)\nval eight_v4 = 8 val eight = four + four\nval eight_v2 = add(1,3) + add(1,3)\nval eight_v3 = 4 + add(1,3)\nval eight_v4 = 8 If we can swap back-and-forth between these expressions anytime, anywhere, without altering their meaning or output, then an expression is referentially transparent.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "12. What is event bubbling and capturing in JavaScript?",
        "answer": "The propagation of events inside the DOM (Document Object Model) is known as 'Event Flow' in JavaScript. The event flow defines the order or sequence in which a particular web page receives an event. Accordingly, event flow (propagation) in JS is dependent on the following aspects: Event Bubbling: With Event Bubbling, the event is captured and handled first by the innermost element, and then propagates to the outermost element. Events propagate up the DOM tree from child elements until the topmost element is handled.\nEvent Capturing: With Event Capturing, the event is captured and handled first by the outermost element, and then propagates to the innermost element. Event cycles propagate starting with the wrapper elements and ending with the target elements that initiated the event cycle. Event Bubbling: With Event Bubbling, the event is captured and handled first by the innermost element, and then propagates to the outermost element. Events propagate up the DOM tree from child elements until the topmost element is handled. Event Bubbling: Event Capturing: With Event Capturing, the event is captured and handled first by the outermost element, and then propagates to the innermost element. Event cycles propagate starting with the wrapper elements and ending with the target elements that initiated the event cycle. Event Capturing: The following diagram will help you to understand the event propagation life cycle.  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "13. Tell me about a project that you worked on and the technologies you used. Why did you choose them?",
        "answer": "With this question, the interviewer can figure out the methodology of the full stack web developer and determine if he is sharp and precise in selecting the right toolset. While explaining the reasons for choosing a particular toolset, you should be as specific as possible. You must demonstrate that you can develop both the front and backend of the web application. Having more experience on one side of the development game than the other is okay, but you should show you are capable of handling both ends of the application.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "14. In the past, what was the best implementation or debugging you did?",
        "answer": "By asking this question, the hiring manager will get an idea of the type and complexity of past projects you have completed. You should clearly state the problems you encountered and the steps you took to overcome them. In addition, you can talk about the lessons you learned from the issue. Conclusion A potential employer doesn't expect applicants to know everything, whether they're freshers or experienced. However, a well-prepared and enthusiastic candidate will undoubtedly stand out. In a full stack developer interview, candidates should be able to demonstrate excellent organizational skills and precision in their work. Also, honesty and transparency pay dividends over the long run. In this article, we have covered the top 30+ Full-Stack developer interview questions & answers for freshers and experienced candidates so you can succeed in your next full-stack developer interview. Questions like those listed above are quick, insightful, and provide key cues that are vital to the interview process. If you review frequently asked full stack developer interview questions and answers, you increase your chances of getting hired. Make sure you review all the questions and answers. We hope to have cleared up your doubts and guided you in the right direction. Good luck with your full stack developer interview! Useful Resources Useful Resources Best Full Stack Developer Courses\nBest Full Stack Projects With Source Code\nFull Stack Engineer Salary – For Freshers and Experienced\nFull Stack Developer Resume\nBest Web Development Courses\nSoftware Engineer / Developer Salary in India\nAngular Interview Questions and Answers\nSoftware Developer vs Software Engineer Best Full Stack Developer Courses Best Full Stack Developer Courses Best Full Stack Projects With Source Code Best Full Stack Projects With Source Code Full Stack Engineer Salary – For Freshers and Experienced Full Stack Engineer Salary – For Freshers and Experienced Full Stack Developer Resume Full Stack Developer Resume Best Web Development Courses Best Web Development Courses Software Engineer / Developer Salary in India Software Engineer / Developer Salary in India Angular Interview Questions and Answers Angular Interview Questions and Answers Software Developer vs Software Engineer Software Developer vs Software Engineer",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "15. State difference between blue/green deployment and rolling deployment.",
        "answer": "Today, the software is rapidly created and features are often changed based on customer needs, and then it is deployed into production. Each organization has its unique way of getting new applications into the production environment. Most organizations follow the standard deployment and release strategies such as Blue-Green and Rolling Deployment. Blue-Green Deployment Strategy: Blue-Green Deployment Strategy: Blue-Green Deployment Strategy: A deployment strategy like this creates two separate infrastructure environments i.e., blue and green. A blue environment contains older code (old version), while a green environment (production) contains the latest code (new version). There is only one live production environment at any given time. Example: For instance, the green environment is live and is receiving all user traffic, while the clone (blue) is idle. Once a new version of an application is ready for release, it can be deployed to the blue environment for testing. As soon as the new release passes testing, application traffic is switched from green to blue. Blue then becomes the live production environment, and Green becomes idle, ready for testing the next release. Example:   Rolling Deployment Strategy Rolling Deployment Strategy Rolling Deployment Strategy Using this deployment strategy, old versions of an application are completely replaced with the new versions by completely replacing the infrastructure on which they run. Example: When a new version must be deployed to all nodes, the new version is deployed to the first node while all other nodes handle end-user traffic. As soon as the new version is successfully installed on the first node, it will begin managing end-user traffic while the new version is being installed on the second node. The process is repeated until all nodes have been successfully upgraded to the new version. Example:  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "16. Explain inversion of control.",
        "answer": "IoC (Inversion of Control), as the name suggests, is a design principle in software engineering. With IoC, different kinds of controls can be inverted in an object-oriented design to attain loose coupling. The term \"controls\" refers to any other responsibilities a class may have other than its primary responsibility. These include controlling the flow of an application, controlling the creation of objects, or controlling the binding and creation of dependent objects. IoC allows classes to be loosely coupled, making testing and maintenance easier.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "1. How to be a full stack developer?",
        "answer": "To become a full stack developer, follow these six steps: become a full stack developer Plan your learning path according to your career goals\nLearn the fundamentals, necessary technologies, and develop the skills you need to be a full-stack developer and necessary technologies.\nLearn from tutorials and videos, but learn to code as well.\nBased on what you learn, create your own project.\nMake a portfolio of your work.\nStart your job search and nail the interview. Plan your learning path according to your career goals Learn the fundamentals, necessary technologies, and develop the skills you need to be a full-stack developer and necessary technologies. Learn from tutorials and videos, but learn to code as well. Based on what you learn, create your own project. Make a portfolio of your work. Start your job search and nail the interview.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. How many types of full-stack developers are there?",
        "answer": "Following are the most common types of full-stack developers based on their specific stacks: MEAN Stack (MongoDB-ExpressJS-AngularJS-NodeJS).\nMERN Stack (MongoDB-ExpressJS-ReactJS-NodeJS).\nLAMP Stack (Linux, Apache, MySQL, PHP).\nLEMP Stack (Linux, Nginx, MySQL, PHP).\nFull-Stack Python.\nFull-Stack Elixir.\nFull-Stack Django.\nFull-Stack Java.\nFull-Stack Ruby on Rails. MEAN Stack (MongoDB-ExpressJS-AngularJS-NodeJS). MERN Stack (MongoDB-ExpressJS-ReactJS-NodeJS). LAMP Stack (Linux, Apache, MySQL, PHP). LEMP Stack (Linux, Nginx, MySQL, PHP). Full-Stack Python. Full-Stack Elixir. Full-Stack Django. Full-Stack Java. Full-Stack Ruby on Rails.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. Which full stack is best?",
        "answer": "One of the most popular tech stacks is the MEAN stack (MongoDB-ExpressJS-AngularJS-NodeJS). MEAN stack has many applications, including cloud application development. MongoDB, Express.js, AngularJS, and Node.js are among the JavaScript technologies in MEAN used to build web applications.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. Is full-stack development a good career?",
        "answer": "Definitely, it's a great career choice. Having a full-stack developer job is one of the most productive careers you can have, and its high level of responsibility makes it one of the most important careers in tech. Full-stack developers do not only specialize in front-end and back-end development but are also experts with a wide range of skill sets and knowledge. Full Stack Developers are in high demand and companies are willing to pay handsomely for those with the right skillset and diverse knowledge. Here's a Resume Sample. Resume Sample",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. How much do full stack developers earn?",
        "answer": "A Full Stack Developer is one of the most highly paid professionals. In India, the average annual salary for a Full Stack Developer is around ₹6,66,697. With 1-4 years of experience, a full-stack developer earns an average of INR 6,53,006-10,00,000. Employees with between 5 and 9 years of experience can expect to earn between INR 12 and 17 lakhs per year. Learn More. Learn More Learn More",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "full-stack-developer"
    }
]